[theme song playing]
[inaudible]
[bell tolling in the distance]
[men singing hymns
in the distance]
You might think this is a curious place
for me to suggest a meeting.
But,
the surprises have only just begun.
[door opens]
You look a little
unsteady, Mr. Shelby.
[door closes]
Take a seat.
You're working together.
Blowing up the Garrison
was your idea.
You who chose me...
It's funny, I thought
the Fenians had a policy...
Enough!
...of not mixing the personal
with politics.
- I said enough.
- I think I'll decide on what is enough.
Who is in charge here then?
Who is in charge?
Let me understand this.
You answer to an agent
of the Crown?
- Very interesting...
- Perhaps we can stick to the agenda.
- Whose agenda?
- There is a form of words here...
- Whose words?
- Arrogant bastard...
I'm not accustomed to being
spoken to like that.
Just come to order.
I am here to listen,
not to the fucking infantry.
Enough! Jesus.
There...
Some weeks ago, Mr. Shelby
carried out a military mission
on behalf of pro-treaty Republicans
here in Birmingham--
You...
- Working for the King...
- There is a unique political situation.
Yeah? How does that feel?
- Let us--
- Tell me...
- How does that fucking feel?
- Temporarily we have a shared interest.
- Should I just stop him laughing?
- You want me to stop laughing?
- Explain this, pal.
- Following the success of your mission...
- We're going to make you do it again.
- Will you shut up?
Can we just conduct
ourselves here, please?
- Conduct ourselves...
- Please.
No one in this room wants to breathe
the same air as anyone else.
Nevertheless--
Nevertheless, the pro-treaty paddies
and the King want the same man dead.
Am I right?
Why him?
Did you ask 'why' in France?
Yeah.
So it's the same answer.
Because...
Why me?
- Because...
Because if anyone connects me to this,
it will be assumed
it was a criminal act
and not a political one.
No.
You need not fear being
connected to the killing
because I will see to it
that no connection is ever made.
You will have complete immunity
after the fact.
But, in the execution, you will get
no help from agents of the Crown.
And we can't be seen to be involved.
You have been chosen, Mr. Shelby.
- And there really is no choice.
- "No" equals bang.
And your man here will shed
no tears as he looks the other way.
Nevertheless, I say no.
[door opens]
[Campbell] Mr. Shelby?
What about your
export license, Mr. Shelby?
You had a deal with Mr. Churchill.
One with the mouth,
Donal Henry, he's a spy.
He's working for the irregulars
against the pro-treaty Paddies.
He reports every fucking word
back to them.
No, it's not possible.
They've both been security
vetted by my own department.
I have men in places
your men can't go.
He meets the anti-treaty
Paddies in the back room
of the Mother Red Cap in Saltley,
sometimes twice a week.
These Irish enemies are
fucking brothers and cousins.
You are stepping into a world
you don't understand.
If what you're saying is true,
he'll be dealt with.
Bring me proof
that the spy is dead
and we have a deal.
- Mr. Shelby.
- Billy boy.
Watch it.
Now, on you go.
[dramatic music playing]
Right, boys. Let's go!
[people shouting and screaming]
Fuck you!
Mario!
[woman screaming]
- Mario!
- [glass shatters]
Come here.
[screaming]
Sabini's day is done.
I'll protect you now.
Oh, shut up.
Stop fucking whinging.
Due to my razor blade
and a few complaints
from the neighbors
about the terrible
fucking music...
Do you want to tell them
or should I?
This place
is under new management.
By order of the Peaky Blinders.
[upbeat music playing]
[whooping]
[laughs]
[gasps]
[yawns]
[clears throat]
- [clears throat]
- [knock at door]
Yes?
Somebody to see you,
Mr. Shelby.
He says he's come about
the position of accounts clerk.
Send him in.
[footsteps retreating]
- [Lizzie] Just through here, sir...
- [man] Thank you.
[footsteps approaching]
Michael...
Vacancy's been filled.
[clears throat]
Not according to
this morning's paper.
At school I was top of the class
in mathematics.
And I did a night school course
in accountancy at Worcester College.
Mum says you've had six different
accountant clerks in the last six months.
When respectable men see
the other things you do, they leave.
Well, I, like Lizzie out there,
already know what you do.
Mum says you want to be 80 percent
legal within two years.
- Three.
- I can help.
I know both sides and you know
you can trust me.
I want to help you, Tommy,
become legal.
Do the right thing.
I want to be proud of this family.
Does Polly know you're here, Michael?
I'm 18 on Friday. I go where I please.
You phone your mother.
Good luck.
[loud knocking at door]
We're not open for winnings yet.
[woman]
I'm here to see Thomas Shelby.
[children chattering excitedly]
I have an appointment.
Come in.
May Carleton.
Mr. Shelby has his proper
meetings in his other office.
This was the address
that he gave me.
- He gave you this address?
- He said it was a gambling den.
I told him that I'd
always wanted to see one
since I am always reading
about them in the papers.
Quite the big scandal in
the Telegraph lately.
Anyway, he said I could come
and have a look.
And now I feel a bit of an idiot
because I'm early and he's late.
- And I have no idea how to behave.
- In a gambling den?
I'll wait in the car.
If I open the door again,
they'll all want to come in.
Like flies.
So what are you?
"What" am I?
To Thomas?
I'm going to train his racehorse.
For Epsom.
You know horses?
Yes.
You?
Born riding.
I slept in a manger
when I was a baby.
I was born riding too.
[door slams shut]
There's a fucking great Riley parked
out there and nobody's watching it.
John, this woman says
she's training Thomas' horse.
He's told us a lot about you.
Don't know where he is, do you?
Sorry, I am late.
[clears throat]
There was
a family matter.
- Esme, keep it locked up for a minute.
- Yes, Thomas.
I'll show you around.
So, be my guest.
That's my brother
Arthur's office.
Down there is my brother
John's office.
That's where we slate
the runners and the riders.
It's so out in the open.
What about the police?
What about them?
When I drove into Small Heath,
I thought I was going to get murdered.
Then I mentioned your name.
It was like being escorted
to see a king.
- You came here to get my girl, right?
- Right.
She looks in very good
condition considering
she's not been out on the gallops.
Curly is the best horseman
in England.
I have a man called Micky
who'd argue the point.
Ah, but Curly here
is half horse himself.
She's blessed. Very blessed.
Well, she's from the best stock.
I'd rather have a colored pony.
Mixed blood is stronger.
- Not to win the Derby.
- Don't like them racing.
Not the way they beat them.
- She's all yours.
- Thank you.
[Charlie] He gets sad
when one leaves.
So what time is
your box van coming?
Midday.
You've got time to take the lady
to the Garrison.
Show her the spa
and the tea rooms.
I'd like that.
Why not?
[clears throat]
I just had it done up.
There was a fire.
It's...
Yep.
What do you drink?
It's so early, but gin.
Goodness. With something?
Like what?
Tonic water or...
Uh... [clears throat]
We have, um...cordial.
There's not much room
in there, but...
[sighs]
You want to fuck me, Mrs. Carleton?
Perhaps because I...
Perhaps because I represent
something to you?
We should have this conversation
before the booze
starts talking for us.
[lights match]
You have a horse...
Yes, I have a horse.
The horse is why I'm here.
Purely that.
And because you
are paying me
a lot of money to train your horse.
That's why I'm here.
Purely that.
Mm.
Good.
Good! Well, a toast, then.
To the horse, to the Derby.
- Cheers.
So is that what you say to women?
I've only done that with them once.
And what if they don't want to fuck?
Then life is simpler.
You want a simple life?
[scoffs]
Do I look like a man
who wants a simple life, eh?
So what do you want?
For what I'm paying you,
Mrs. Carleton,
I want a horse that'll pay out
at Epsom on an each way bet.
Before I took your account...
[clears throat]
I did some credit checks on you.
Apparently you don't exist.
My existence is questionable.
Gypsies don't like registers.
You see I'm not a Gypsy
like you mean.
But you did register for France.
I also sent your name to the war office.
I have friends there.
You won two medals
for gallantry.
Does that really impress you,
Mrs. Carleton?
Call me May.
[door opens]
[door closes]
Charlie says
the box van is here.
Thank you, Finn.
[door opens]
You know, I still don't know
what you're going to call your horse.
The horse will be called
Grace's Secret.
I told him he definitely
can't take the job.
He said, "All right,
I'll move to London then."
I said I won't give in
to blackmail.
No is no.
Well, that settles it then.
I'll give the job to
the other candidate.
He is much better
qualified anyway.
Michael did City and Guilds.
Six months.
Yeah. But he doesn't
know racing, Pol.
He knows horses
but he doesn't know racing.
This other boy,
he knows racing.
He's good. He is a fast learner.
What if Michael really leaves?
You've just got to let him go, Pol.
He will get a job
in an office in London.
I'm sure he'll write to you.
He made a big speech.
About wanting to help you build up
a respectable business.
He's like his dad.
He can make me cry.
There are trains to London.
So I just let him leave?
Every month or so he'd be back.
Unless of course he meets a girl...
Then who knows?
Oh, my God.
You want him to do this job.
Polly, I want what you want.
What about this other
more qualified candidate?
Hm.
Well, I lied. There isn't one.
How much are you paying?
- The advertised rate.
- Like hell.
- Three bob.
- Three and six.
- Four.
Four it is.
- I love him, Tom.
- I know.
That's why I'll keep him away
from the old business.
And put him charge of the new.
Agreed?
Agreed.
Well, Finn, you have got
two choices, mild or mild.
- Mild.
- Here you go.
- [door opens]
- There he is. Look.
[all cheering]
Happy birthday, Michael.
Eighteen years old.
You're a man today.
- Give him a drink, John boy.
- There you go.
And after that, we will go
and find you a lady of the night.
Arthur!
Michael... [clears throat]
What is that?
[Thomas]
So you are never late for work.
[John] Welcome to
the business, Michael.
- Welcome to the business.
- Thank you.
Right, come on, let's get him drunk.
Come here, you.
- All right. Whiskey.
- No whiskey.
He's got work tomorrow.
Give him only dark mild.
A toast...
- A toast.
- To Michael.
- To Michael!
[door opens]
You all right?
[clears throat]
- What is it? Just us?
- Just us.
[Polly] Are we celebrating?
Just taste this.
What do you think, Arthur?
Yeah, it is good, good stuff, really nice.
Too good for the Garrison.
I suppose we could shift it to
the toffs at the Eden club.
Why? What is it?
That is part of an export drive.
We now have our secure warehouse
in Camden Town
and secure passage to
the Poplar docks.
So on Monday morning
we'll be sending out
our first export crate.
A crate of Riley car spares
bound for Halifax, Nova Scotia.
Where there is prohibition?
Where there is prohibition.
All over Canada and America
people are making
their own booze.
In bath tubs.
But rich people in New York,
in Toronto and Boston
are still paying a lot of money
for the real stuff.
So on Monday, the first
Shelby Company crate
will contain 1000 Riley carburetors
but hidden in the packing,
will be 500 bottles
of the finest quality
single malt Scotch whiskey.
We Shelbys have a license
granted by the Minister
of the Empire himself,
which means our crates
won't be searched.
And, Polly, all of the whiskey
will be packed at the docks
so Michael can do the books
without being involved.
Like I've been telling you
all for a year now,
motor cars are the future.
[men speaking indistinctly]
So, how's your life been, Tom?
On the up, Johnny. On the up.
Yeah, but, Tom, really, come on.
How is it?
You know I hate to see you
not even married yet.
I have a fine-looking cousin,
she would make your life hell.
You deserve her.
[laughs]
We haven't had a good old
wedding in a long time.
Have you had a look inside
these boxes then, Johnny?
Now why do I want to look
at car parts, Tommy?
When I haven't even got a car.
Faith in family is a fine thing, eh?
And I won't even be counting.
If 25 becomes 24,
then 24 it is.
You know I am no good
with numbers, Tom.
But if 24 ever became 23,
then that would be tax.
And we don't pay tax.
No, Tom.
Good man!
[upbeat music playing]
I put an iron door on.
And we put iron bars on the windows
and across the skylights.
Good.
So what will you be
keeping in here, Tommy?
Temptation, Billy. Temptation.
[moaning]
[door opens loudly]
Morning, Arthur.
I was just passing.
[Arthur]
I think I am in fucking love.
Drink!
[exhales]
She don't know where to look.
Whiskey, Tommy?
- No. I've got a long drive ahead.
- You off home?
Mm-hmm.
Eventually.
To Birmingham.
What's this?
Olives.
Yes, that's miscellaneous.
Um...
Olives. On sticks.
You know, with little bits
of fucking onion and things.
That's what it is.
We've taken 600 pounds
on olives.
With little bits of onion.
I told you, Arthur.
The dealers sell the cocaine
and we take a cut.
We don't sell it direct.
The Home Secretary
is cracking down
and I don't want this to fuck up
everything else. Understand?
I understand.
How much of that 600 came out
of your pocket?
It's under control.
I put you down here because people
are scared of you, Arthur.
But if you don't straighten up,
it'll be John's turn in London.
No need, I can handle it.
It's under control?
It's under control.
Fucking tidy profit, though, eh?
It's happening, Tom.
Good.
Straighten up, soldier.
[door closes]
Yes, sir, Sergeant Major!
[turns off ignition]
[clears throat]
What's your business?
Sorry, I'm lost.
Yeah, well, you can't stop here.
Move on.
[starts ignition]
Twenty-three seconds.
It's all right, Ada,
it'll be Andrew for me.
Hello!
I'm looking for Ada.
Who are you?
- [door closes]
- Ada...
I asked you a question.
It's all right, James.
This is my brother.
Who's he?
- He rents a room.
- You need to rent out rooms?
Actually, she doesn't charge rent.
He's a writer.
Which means he's skint.
You get up late these days, Ada.
I go to bed late.
Where's Karl?
What do you want, Tommy?
Oh, God, before you start sizing
him up for a wedding suit,
he's not interested in me.
Or in girls of any kind.
- Ada?
- What?
Tommy won't judge you.
He sure as hell won't go to the police.
Look, I'll go and get dressed.
James. I'm Thomas.
Pleased to meet you.
Could I have a minute
with my sister, please?
Yes, of course.
[clears throat]
So, does your lodger know
your name?
Yeah. Thorne.
You think I'd tell anybody anything else?
Your Brummie boys
are all over the papers.
Just one last push, eh?
Then you'll go legit.
Just one more obstacle to get round.
Then it'll all be straight.
- Actually, yes!
- [scoffs]
Personally, I find it
quite amusing.
Men like you are becoming
very fashionable down here.
No society party in London is complete
without a gangster
for the girls to go giddy for.
Anyway, what is it
that you want?
I don't have any children, Ada.
So I have set up a trust fund.
The beneficiaries will be
John's kids and Karl.
In order for Karl to benefit,
I need your signature.
I've set up an account.
And money will be transferred
in the event of my death.
It will set them up
for a new life.
Are you sick?
I'm just doing what
any ordinary man would.
Putting my affairs in order.
Did you know they were going
to take the Eden club?
I know about the Eden club. Yes.
Did you know they were going to
do it before they did it?
Because that's the one who
is in charge, isn't it?
The one who knows before it happens.
I know what I know.
If you don't know,
then you don't fucking know, do you?
Did you know they was going to
take Wimbledon dogs?
- And Harringay? And the trotting tracks?
- Uh...
Talk, all right?
I genuinely want to hear you.
- You've lost control, Alfie.
- Have I?
Everybody knows.
- Talk to me, Alfie.
- Talk to you?
All right, I will talk to you.
I will fucking tell you how it was, right?
What happened was this...
All the time you were talking
about dirty fucking Jews.
All the fucking time...
Dirty fucking Jews, dirty kikes,
dirty dustbin lids.
You wanna talk about
not getting into places?
Everybody makes fucking jokes.
I didn't know you had
no sense of humor.
And you were pushing
everybody around.
And I am not going
to fucking mention
the great big fuck off
elephant in the room.
Look, Alfie...
How many of my bookies
worked Epsom this last May?
None. None.
Not one.
So, for a few fucking jokes and Epsom,
you fucking invite a tribe
of savages into the city
and just fucking clog
the fucking gates!
I'm sorry, what are you saying, mate?
I'm saying
I am sorry about the Jew thing.
- Are you saying you are sorry?
- Yeah.
- You are sorry about the Jew thing?
- Really?
- Yeah.
I want that in writing.
Write that down. He said I'm sorry.
[man starts writing]
And also write down
that all our bookies
can go back to Epsom...
- He didn't say that.
- Who's asking you?
Write it down.
It's all right. Come on.
Alfie is an old friend.
My friend.
Now. Admit it.
The Peaky Blinders
is out of control.
Yeah. They are out
of fucking control, mate.
They came down the canal
and spread like the fucking clap.
Right.
- So now they are everybody's problem.
- Yeah.
- Alfie.
- Mm.
You and me, we've been fighting
since we were at school.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Now also, we've been friends.
- Yeah.
You know it goes
backwards and forwards.
How much better is it
when we're friends?
Oh, it's much better, mate. Yeah.
You write that down.
Mm.
So what we are doing here is
we are writing down
some kind of a deal thing, right?
- Yeah. A written deal.
- A written deal.
Good, then why don't we discuss
the border between the Italians
and the Jews going back
to Farringdon Road?
Farrington Road--
- Yeah. Farringdon Road.
- Fuck. That is ancient history.
Write down
Farrington Road.
- No, no. Write down Camden Road.
- Farringdon Road.
- Farringdon Road...
- Camden Road...
Write down Camden Road.
Just write down peace.
Just write down peace
between the Jews and the Italians.
And war against the Gypsies.
Hm.
Fuck.
- [door opens]
- Mr. Thomas Shelby, madam.
[door closes]
Nice house.
Would you like a whiskey?
Scotch or Irish.
Irish.
Sorry for the short notice.
I was passing.
We're not quite on
the Birmingham Road.
A small diversion.
Sixty miles. I checked.
That's a small diversion
these days.
So I am a small diversion.
Good.
Your horse is still out
on the gallops.
But I had Micky
prepare this report.
You can read it now if you like,
then we'll go and see her.
[clears throat]
- Is there enough light for you to read?
- Yes, it's fine.
It's getting quite late.
Micky says she has the lungs
of an elephant.
She is nimble in the heavy going
but bounces a little on hard ground.
Sorry, I'll let you read.
So he thinks she will favor good
to soft ground, eh?
- A little juice in the grass.
- Mm.
Well, that is good for Epsom.
Does he think she's not
good enough for Epsom?
She needs a lot of work.
The race board will need convincing.
I imagine you have some influence.
Hm.
That's the suggested program
for the next two months.
Your glass is empty.
Yes, it's fine.
Are you hungry?
Yes. A bit.
I can prepare something.
Do you have engine oil?
Before I set off for Birmingham,
the car needs oil.
I'm sure my husband kept some
in the garage. I'll get someone to do it.
This evening or tomorrow?
We are so far from anywhere,
people usually stay over.
Especially before cars and carriages,
people used to stay over all the time.
But I have a car.
Yes.
And you have
engine oil.
Probably.
But it would be very usual.
What would?
For a guest to stay. We have
a whole wing. A guest wing.
Oh, good.
You have a guest wing.
Well... [exhales]
May?
Have a smoke.
Thank you.
Ignore this. It's actually all right.
I put all his photos
in a drawer and locked it.
As if that was going
to make it different.
I am like a fucking lighthouse keeper.
Out here on my own.
Keeping his flame burning.
But of course,
when anyone sees a lighthouse
they steer clear, don't they?
Now, do you have a map?
Of the house. Do you have a map?
Because
I'm not going to be able
to find me way in the dark.
You see, at midnight,
I'm going to leave my wing.
And I'm going to come
and find you.
And I' m going to turn the handle
of your bedroom door
without making a sound.
And none of the maids will know.
You don't know maids.
They hear a pin drop.
If there is a man in the house,
they listen.
They take turns.
So let them listen.
Right.
Day rate, seven shillings.
Loading unloading.
Night rate, three.
Total ten.
Let's go and get a drink.
No, I'm all right.
Come on, it's pay day.
- Everybody has a drink on pay day.
- Not me!
You think your mom don't have
a drink on pay day?
You think the Lord Almighty
don't have a drink on pay day?
Man, it's on fire out there.
Women from the BSA offices.
Honest.
They go out on their own
without men these days.
In twos and threes now.
Mickey, they go out in twos and threes
and buy their own drinks.
The Marquis.
That's where the BSA secretaries go.
Look.
They won't serve a black man
without a Shelby by his side.
So you're using me.
Yeah. Come on.
- [people talking and laughing]
- [swing music playing]
I told you. I fucking told you.
This city is going mad.
Girls go out on their own now.
Two pints of dark mild, please.
Fuck that. We're Peaky boys.
Two whiskeys.
You get used to it.
Then you can't stop.
[man whistles]
I don't drink with blacks.
Here we fucking go.
Paddy, they're okay.
Not with me they're not.
- I don't drink in pubs with blacks.
- So leave.
Look, my dad is
the preacher round here.
- He has connections. Ask anybody.
- [scoffs]
I couldn't give
a fuck who he is.
I'm telling you
to leave it, Paddy.
And I'm telling this darkie
to get out of here.
- You know something? Fuck off.
- It's all right, Isaiah, leave it.
- We'll go to my cousin's pub.
- I like it here.
You fucking nigger.
- [boys shouting]
- [people screaming]
[bartender] Paddy!
The white kid's a Peaky Blinder!
He's Polly Shelby's son.
Are you fucking suicidal?
Sir? Sir, I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
- Get out!
- I'm sorry.
- Get out the fucking pub.
- I really didn't know.
Fuck! Let's go! Let's go!
We ordered some drinks?
And we are going
to drink them.
His face, man.
Did you see his fucking face?
You punch like
a fucking kangaroo.
I seen one once in a circus.
You punch like that.
All right, anyway,
I need a fucking drink.
- The drinks are on you!
- It's on me? You just got paid!
And make it a whiskey.
[people chattering]
Fucking hell, it's packed
in here, isn't it?
So it's as easy as that?
It's as easy as that, John boy.
London. You wouldn't believe it.
- Finn, stick your head in a bucket.
- No.
The women, John boy, the women.
There is this one,
she's a dancer, right?
She can do things with her...
If Finn would
just piss off,
- I'd explain a little bit better.
- Yeah.
- Well, if it's so good, why are you here?
- A decent pint.
The cockneys can't get that right.
He misses us, Finn.
That's what it is.
[door opens]
[Arthur] Here they are, look.
Junior Peaky boys.
What's happened to you,
have you been scrapping?
- Oh.
- Some idiots at the Marquis of Lorne.
They tried to stop me and Isiah
from drinking but it is all right.
We fought them off.
Arthur, we had to stand
our ground and we did.
The Marquis, eh?
Where's your dad?
- Preaching.
- Right.
Don't nick any of me chips, Finn!
- Where are you going?
- We won't be long.
[door closes]
Where are they going?
The Marquis of Lorne.
Shame.
It was a nice pub.
[erotic music playing]
[door closes]
[breathing heavily]
Ah! Ah! Ah!
Looks like the big bastard got cut.
You didn't have
to do that for me!
We didn't do it
for you, Michael.
We did it for the good name
of the company.
None of this happened, all right?
Come on. Let's go
and get that drink.
[door opens]
[footsteps approaching]
[breathes deeply]
The date has been set.
Three weeks from today.
You checked out his house?
There's coppers all over it.
You'll take care of them?
No. It would arouse suspicion.
You'll have to deal
with them yourself.
And if a copper gets killed?
There will be no
consequences for you.
I have given you my word.
Which I know
to be worthless.
That is why I have
been settling my affairs
in the event of my death.
[chuckling] And making your peace
with God, perhaps?
Good luck with that.
I have made arrangements.
With men I trust.
If I should die,
then you will die.
Know that.
[footsteps retreating]
[exhales heavily]
Ritz Hotel.
[clears throat]
London, Piccadilly.
[ringing]
Hello?
[hangs up phone]
- Who was that?
- Call got cut.
I guess the telephone lines in
England are not so good, huh?
[theme song playing]